<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manas Kashyap</title>
    <description>A Developer at building phase.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 09:37:32 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 09:37:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic Linux Commands -1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Blog, I am going to tell 10 Basic Linux Commands. 
This Blog is part of a series that is going to be released soon .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-linux&quot;&gt;What is Linux?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux is best known as the most used open source operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the term “Linux” to refer to the Linux kernel, but also the set of programs, tools, and services that are typically bundled together with the Linux kernel to provide all of the necessary components of a fully functional operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://manas-kashyap.github.io/jekyll/2018/11/03/Why-linux/&quot;&gt;Why to use linux?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-linux-command-line-shell-or-terminal-&quot;&gt;What is Linux Command Line ,shell or Terminal ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A terminal, shell is a program that receives commands from the user and gives it to the OS to process, and it shows the output.
Linux’s shell is its main part. Its distros come in GUI (graphical user interface), but basically, Linux has a CLI (command line interface). In this tutorial, we are going to cover the basic commands that we use in the shell of Linux..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;to-open-the-terminal-press-ctrlaltt-in-ubuntu-debian-or-press-altf2-type-in-gnome-terminal-and-press-enter-in-raspberry-pi-type-in-lxterminal-there-is-also-a-gui-way-too-by-searching-for-terminal-in-start-menu&quot;&gt;To open the terminal, press Ctrl+Alt+T in Ubuntu, Debian, or press Alt+F2, type in gnome-terminal, and press enter. In Raspberry Pi, type in lxterminal. There is also a GUI way too by searching for terminal in start menu.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;linux-commands&quot;&gt;Linux Commands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) ls&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the &lt;strong&gt;“ls”&lt;/strong&gt; command to know what files are in the directory you are in. You can see all the hidden files by using the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ls -a”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) cd&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the &lt;strong&gt;“cd”&lt;/strong&gt; command to go to a directory. For example, if you are in the home folder, and you want to go to the downloads folder, then you can type in “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;cd Downloads”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Remember, this command is case sensitive, and you have to type in the name of the folder exactly as it is. 
But there is a problem with these commands. Imagine you have a folder named “Raspberry Pi”. In this case, when you type in “cd Raspberry Pi”, the shell will take the second argument of the command as a different one, so you will get an error saying that the directory does not exist. Here, you can use a backward slash. That is, you can use &lt;strong&gt;“cd Raspberry\ Pi”&lt;/strong&gt; in this case. Spaces are denoted like this: &lt;em&gt;If you just type “cd” and press enter, it takes you to the home directory.&lt;/em&gt; To go back from a folder to the folder before that, you can type &lt;strong&gt;“cd ..”&lt;/strong&gt; . The two dots represent back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) mkdir &amp;amp; rmdir&lt;/strong&gt; - the command when you need to create a folder or a directory. For example, if you want to make a directory called “freshers”, then you can type “&lt;em&gt;mkdir freshers”&lt;/em&gt;.
Remember, as told before, if you want to create a directory named &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“fresher 2k18”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, then you can type &lt;em&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;mkdir freshers\ 2k18&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/em&gt;. 
Use &lt;strong&gt;rmdir&lt;/strong&gt; to delete a directory. But &lt;em&gt;rmdir&lt;/em&gt; can only be used to delete an empty directory. 
&lt;em&gt;To delete a directory containing files, use rm&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) rm&lt;/strong&gt; - This command is used to delete files and directories.  Use &lt;strong&gt;“rm -r*“&lt;/strong&gt; to delete just the directory. It deletes both the folder and the files it contains when using only the rm command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;warning--never-do--sudo-rm--rf--it-will-delete-all-the-files-in-your-root-directory-leading-to-shutting-down-of-system&quot;&gt;Warning:- never do , “sudo rm -rf /*”, it will delete all the files in your root directory leading to shutting down of system.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) touch&lt;/strong&gt; - This command is used to create a file. It can be anything, from an empty txt file to an empty zip file. For example, “touch new.txt”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) man &amp;amp; –help&lt;/strong&gt; - To know more about a command and how to use it, use the man command. It shows the manual pages of the command. For example, &lt;em&gt;“man cd”&lt;/em&gt; shows the manual pages of the cd command. Typing in the command name and the argument helps it show which ways the command can be used &lt;em&gt;(e.g., cd –help).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) cp&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the &lt;em&gt;cp&lt;/em&gt; command to copy files through the command line. It takes two arguments: &lt;em&gt;The first is the location of the file to be copied, the second is where to copy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) mv&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the mv command to move files through the command line. &lt;em&gt;We can also use the mv command to rename a file&lt;/em&gt;. For example, if we want to rename the file “text” to “new”, we can use “mv text new”. It takes the two arguments, just like the cp command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) cat&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the cat command to display the contents of a file. It is usually used to easily view programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10) uname&lt;/strong&gt; - Use uname to show the information about the system your Linux distro is running. Using the command “uname -a” prints most of the information about the system. This prints the kernel release date, version, processor type, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tips and Tricks for Using Linux Command Line&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the clear command to clear the terminal .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TAB can be used to fill up in terminal. For example, You just need to type “cd Doc” and then TAB and the terminal fills the rest up and makes it “cd Documents”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ctrl+C can be used to stop any command in terminal safely. If it doesn’t stop with that, then Ctrl+Z can be used to force stop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can exit from the terminal by using the exit command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can power off or reboot the computer by using the command sudo halt and sudo reboot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-more-commands-visit-here&quot;&gt;For more commands visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://ss64.com/bash/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some commands that will help you while starting in Linux terminal .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully it helps you .&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 17:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/06/Basic-Linux-Commands-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/06/Basic-Linux-Commands-1/</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>Command Line</category>
        
        <category>Basics</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to install Tor-Browser in Linux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Blog, I will be sharing a quick guide on how to install Tor-browser in your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-tor&quot;&gt;What is Tor?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tor software protects you by bouncing your communications around a distributed network of relays run by volunteers all around the world: it prevents somebody watching your Internet connection from learning what sites you visit, it prevents the sites you visit from learning your physical location, and it lets you access sites which are blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor Browser lets you use Tor on Microsoft Windows, Apple MacOS, or GNU/Linux without needing to install any software. It can run off a USB flash drive, comes with a pre-configured web browser to protect your anonymity, and is self-contained (portable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know more read the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/documentation.html.en&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s too much of info, get me to the installation part&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-install-tor&quot;&gt;How to install Tor.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) “For Kali Linux and Debian repository”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;sudo-apt-get-install-tor&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install tor&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Download and Running TOR Bundle
For this, you need a little grip of some basic Linux command like wget, cd and changing the permission of files.
So, let’s start
I) Let’s get the TOR Bundle (latest version as on 05-11-2018), we will be using “wget” tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Let’s get to the terminal using ctrl+alt+t (for many Desktop environment, Defaultly setup).
Lets get to the directory where you want to install it, lets suppose Documents is the place , so the command will be &lt;em&gt;cd Documents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we will download the TOR bundle using wget or you can do it manually from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy.html.en&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; (but doing manually will Download it to the Downoads folder) , but from terminal we will use &lt;em&gt;“wget https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/8.0.3/tor-browser-linux64-8.0.3_en-US.tar.xz”&lt;/em&gt; (latest bundle as per 05/11/18) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II) Now we will extract it from the zipped filee that we just downloaded.
For that we will use &lt;em&gt;“tar -xvzf https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/8.0.3/tor-browser-linux64-8.0.3_en-US.tar.xz”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;III) Now we can see the files will be extracted to a new folder named tor-browser(tab completion completes it)
We will go to that folder using &lt;em&gt;“cd tor-browser(tab completion)”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IV) Now by typing &lt;em&gt;“ls -la”&lt;/em&gt; , you can see a number of files in which one is “start-tor-browser.desktop”
so , to run and setup things , we will use command &lt;em&gt;“chmod +x start-tor-browser.desktop &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./start-tor-browser.desktop “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;chmod changes the permission of the file of start-tor-browser.desktop file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hope-it-helps-you-all&quot;&gt;Hope it helps you all.&lt;/h5&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 01:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/06/How-to-install-tor-browser-in-linux/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/06/How-to-install-tor-browser-in-linux/</guid>
        
        <category>Proxy</category>
        
        <category>Browser</category>
        
        <category>Tor</category>
        
        <category>Installation</category>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Journey with Tech -1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Blog, I will be sharing my experience and a look back of my journey from where I started.
Yeah, it’s not a technical blog but surely it’s a technical guy journey overview. 
Please read till last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Date every technology before you get settled for one” - Anonymous&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-nervous-guys&quot;&gt;A nervous guys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this journey started in 2016 when I got admission in Amity University, I still remember the first day when we had an introduction class, where everyone was giving an intro about themselves to the teachers and I was sitting there and hearing intros. Many students have already started with technical things or have done a lot of work in their startups. And when I got the chance to speak I became nervous as, I too wanted to speak something cool I have done, but when I recall everything till that moment, I haven’t done anything great and that nervousness came to my voice and I started to stammer, although somehow I spoke about myself and where I belong and that’s it and I sat back .
But I got a reality check about my confidence plus what I have done till now. I was really nervous and wanted to do something great. Well, I was a computer student in my school, but never explored it, as I never thought that, there are many options in exploring it plus I used to stick to the syllabus for the computer. And, now it was coming back that I should have explored options and should have tried things as many had done in my class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;turning-point&quot;&gt;Turning Point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The turning point in my life was a workshop by my college club on Linux and python. Well, I wanted to do something great in my life and wanted to learn technical things, so I used to attend every college club workshop, and there was one workshop which changed my life. In my class 11,12 read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://whatis.techtarget.com/definition/open-source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt; and there i learnt about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.org/&quot;&gt;linux&lt;/a&gt; . So, I was really excited plus i wanted to know what is really linux. So , i went to linux workshop and there came some alumni of our college who have already ecelled and tried linux in their time and they gave a brief knowledge about linux , and really i thought i should &lt;a href=&quot;https://manas-kashyap.github.io/jekyll/2018/11/03/Why-linux/&quot;&gt;use linux&lt;/a&gt;. There i learnt about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;python&lt;/a&gt; too , and python programming langugae really attracted me as it was really new plus compatible for me to work on .
From that day I started to use Linux and python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-technical-things&quot;&gt;More technical things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was exploring things, I came to know about game developing and tried my luck there also, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://unity3d.com/&quot;&gt;unity 3D&lt;/a&gt;, then tried to design things in 3D and also 2D graphics designing using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.photoshop.com/&quot;&gt;photoshop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autodesk.com/education/free-software/maya&quot;&gt;Autodesk Maya&lt;/a&gt;, android development and so on,  So basically I tried my best to learn every technology I could, in this journey I encountered some super awesome seniors, and some really helpful communities when it came for open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-contribution-to-open-source&quot;&gt;My first contribution to Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, well I remember my first contribution was in a website of a technical club of my college itself where i did a minor change in the css component of the website .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-biggest-contribution&quot;&gt;My biggest contribution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, i really don’t think i have done any big contribution till now , well the contribution that made my name in Open Source contributors name is &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/ManasKashyap&quot;&gt;My Debian Packaging&lt;/a&gt; and contribution to &lt;a href=&quot;http://hamaralinux.org&quot;&gt;HamaraLinux project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-this-blog&quot;&gt;Why This Blog??&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure many readers who are going to read this blog will have one thing in mind &lt;em&gt;“Why this Blog?”&lt;/em&gt;. So, for them, the answer is I have encountered many students who are feeling very low because they don’t have any prior technical knowledge and that leads to loosing of their self-confidence.
For, those students just one kind of advice, try your best and leave the rest. I also started without any prior knowledge and yeah i am at a place where i didnt expect i will be in upcoming years. 
This blog is just to let you know yeah, you all are not alone who are starting with things now, just don’t feel low as it can create many bad thoughts in your mind, as I have encountered with those thoughts and it created really a lot of bad phase in my college journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-is-just-a-small-part-of-the-bigger-story-which-will-come-soon-part--1-is-this&quot;&gt;This is just a small part of the bigger story which will come soon. (Part -1 is this)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;hope-it-helps-you-all-&quot;&gt;Hope it helps you all .&lt;/h5&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 01:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/05/My-journey-with-Tech-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/05/My-journey-with-Tech-1/</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>Open source</category>
        
        <category>Journey</category>
        
        <category>A look back</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Linux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Blog, I am going to answer some questions over Linux and also state why I use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux is best known as the most used open source operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the term “Linux” to refer to the Linux kernel, but also the set of programs, tools, and services that are typically bundled together with the Linux kernel to provide all of the necessary components of a fully functional operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-should-use-linux-over-windows&quot;&gt;Why I should use Linux over windows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well i started using Linux because , first of all its &lt;a href=&quot;https://whatis.techtarget.com/definition/open-source&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; , secondly at that time when I started using Linux is , I had an old laptop Compaq 621, with 2gb ram and intel core duo , I wanted to use new software but my laptop was 32 bit and was a not great supporter of many software, so at that time one of my friends told me to use Linux as its a lightweight OS and to my amaze it was running efficiently on my old laptop and with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more reason behind my usage of Linux journey was the new look which really attracted me, yeah I wanted to feel that new look, well in windows too we have many themes and transformation pack, but I really wanted to feel the original look of Linux system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, there is strong community support for Linux over the Internet through various forums. Any question posed in forums will usually get a quick response as a lot of volunteers are online and working to solve the problems due to their passion for Linux. The paid support option is also available for commercial enterprises, with companies like Red Hat and Novell offering 24×7 support for critical applications and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-meant-by-linux-distro&quot;&gt;What is meant by Linux distro?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Linux world, there are hundreds of different flavors of a distro. Examples include Debian, Ubuntu and Red Hat (among many others).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, a distribution is any deployment of software and isn’t specifically Linux. Usually, in this case, you’ll hear it referred to as a “distribution of software.” Despite this, the term “distro” is nearly always used in a Linux context. So, while a distribution of software is a generic term for any bundle of software, a distro is nearly always a flavor of Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-linux-distro-i-have-used-and-i-am-using-currently&quot;&gt;Which Linux distro I have used and I am using currently&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till date i have used many different distros of linux , i have used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxmint.com/&quot;&gt;Linux mint&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;http://hamaralinux.org&quot;&gt;Hamara Linux&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;arch linux&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kali.org/&quot;&gt;kali&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.debian.org&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.debian.org/releases/sid/&quot;&gt;Debian SID&lt;/a&gt; as I need my os to be updated with new packages and not to be waiting till a new release, plus I do a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.debian.org/Packaging&quot;&gt;Debian packaging&lt;/a&gt; and for that, I need Debian SID machine.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 17:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/03/Why-linux/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/11/03/Why-linux/</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>Open source</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
